Oyshee Saha Roy

+19024480058 | **E**: juni.roy5@gmail.com 68 Larksmere Ct. Markham, ON L3R 3R1

https://oysheesaharoy.com/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/oysheesaharoy/

Professional Summary

User Experience Researcher and Designer with experience in conducting user studies, data analysis and designing different interactive interfaces. Senior System Engineer with 3.5 years of experience in working as a Java and Mendix Developer using Agile methodology. Experienced in working as an Analyst for Dalhousie Analytics, Dalhousie University. Involved in business requirement gathering, identifying gaps, effort estimations and implementing solutions with adherence to best practices and development guidelines.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS3, shell scripting
- MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- Tableau, Mendix, GitHub, Jira, Mantis, Bitbucket, Putty
- Anaconda Distributions, Eclipse, • Pycharm, Sublime text, Google Colab, • Microsoft Visual Studio, Notepad++, Powerpoint, Excel, Marvel
- Python, Java, BrightScript, JavaScript, Data Science and Machine Learning Algorithms
 - Qualitative and Quantitative data analysis
 - Conducting user studies
 - Designing prototypes for applications
 - Design and build static and dynamic website
 - Designing using Inkscape

Work History

Student Analyst Dalhousie University| Halifax, NS

02/2019 - 08/2019

- Participated in requirements meetings and data mapping sessions to understand business needs
- Designed and developed schema data models
- Fetched JSON data from RESTful APIs. The fetched data were cleaned and stored in tables in PostgreSQL
- The collected data was further processed using Fuzzy matching
- Helped solve diverse program problems with in-depth analysis

- Analyzed data were visualized using matplotlib, plotly, and Dash apps
- Updated organizational subsystems to improve and streamline data collection

Residence Assistant and Guest Sign-in Staff Dalhousie University| Halifax, NS

08/2018-04/2019

- Key responsibilities include interacting with students, hosting residence events and programming, role-modeling, peer counselling and ensuring students' rights to a positive living-learning environment are respected
- Responsible for working with Residence Life Staff and Dal Security to promote a safe and inclusive living environment

Senior Systems Engineer Infosys Ltd| Trivandrum, India

08/2014-12/2017

Roku

- Development of front-end scripts for Roku boxes.
- Participated in all phases of system development life cycle, from requirements analysis through system implementation
- Involved in sprint planning, stand-ups in an Agile environment
- Designing and development of Electronic programming guides
- Development of Video on Demand screen, video playing features, notification and warning messages, and other features of live as well as video on demand streaming services
- Involved in development, dev testing, quality assurance of Roku application

TNT

- Development and maintenance of Mendix application solutions including forms, entities, microflows, transactions, and domain models
- Performed Unit Testing as per project and client-based guidelines
- Participated in all phases of system development life cycle, from requirements analysis through system implementation
- Involved in maintaining databases of transactions, employee history, delivery status and goods details
- Development of features of applications, directly interacting with clients and providing solutions.

Loreal

- Development and maintenance of POS application
- Experience in handling loyalty-based program

Education

Master in Computer Science Dalhousie University| Halifax, NS

10/2019

Thesis: Framework to Guide Designing of Interactive Tools for Art galleries

Bachelor of Technology| Computer Science WBUT| Kolkata, India

06/2014

Projects

Promoting ACT (Acceptance and Commitment Therapy) through mobile application

- Conducted user-studies (online survey, interviews, and user feedback) at different stages of the project
- Built low-fidelity and high-fidelity prototypes and wireframes for mobile application
- Conducted A/B testing
- Conducted Heuristic evaluations and collected user feedback on the prototype

Heart Disease Prediction using Data Mining Techniques

In this project, decision tree classifiers as well as a probability-based classifier. The algorithms that were used are Naïve Bayes classifier, J48 algorithm and Random forest classifier. We have taken an existing patient data set of Cleveland from UCI repository to test and analyze the algorithms.

Publication and Certification

Oyshee Saha Roy and James Blustein, "Protocol to build a Framework for Designing an Interactive Tool for Art Gallery Visitors"," HUMAN'19: 2nd International Workshop on Human Factors in Hypertext Proceedings", 2019, Hof, Germany.

Introduction to User Experience Principles and Processes
(An online non-credit course authorized by University of Michigan and offered through Coursera)

References

Claudia Rangel, PhD, Chief Analyst and Managing Director, Dalhousie Analytics **E:** cl221087@dal.ca

Dr Jamie Blustein, Associate Professor, Dalhousie University **E:**jamie@cs.dalprofs.org